♪The golden phoenix is flying in the colorful sky♪
♪ طائر الفينيق الذهبي يطير في السماء الملونة ♪
♪Such a rare and perfect match♪
♪ مثل هذه المباراة النادرة والمثالية
♪I won't be oppressed by the palace rules♪
♪ لن أكون مضطهدة بقواعد القصر ♪
♪Love and time are rarely aligned♪
نادرًا ما يتماشى الحب والوقت
♪But it's such a perfect match♪
♪ لكنها مباراة مثالية ♪
♪Long live the Queen? I prefer a sweet smile♪
تحيا الملكة؟  انا افضل ابتسامة حلوة ♪
♪One is willing to tolerate while the other is willing to hit♪
واحد على استعداد للتسامح والآخر مستعد للضرب ♪
♪Bring it on, my rival♪
اجلبه على منافسي
♪No might can fly up to the sky♪
♪ لا يمكن أن يطير إلى السماء
♪It doesn't affect my elegance at all♪
♪ لا يؤثر على أناقتي إطلاقا
♪Great at writing family rules♪
رائع في كتابة قواعد الأسرة ♪
♪And bullying the imperial bodyguards♪
♪ والتنمر على حراس الإمبراطور ♪
♪When I turn around and flash my smile, tears will be shed♪
♪ عندما أستدير وأومض ابتسامتي ، ستذرف الدموع
♪I'm here to annoy you♪
♪ أنا هنا لأزعجك ♪
♪The Queen has arrived! Nothing is a big deal to me♪
وصلت الملكة!  لا شيء مهم بالنسبة لي ♪
♪Shouldering the responsibility as your virtuous and capable wife♪
تحمل المسئولية كزوجة فاضلة وقادرة
♪The Queen has arrived! She brings happiness to all♪
وصلت الملكة!  إنها تجلب السعادة للجميع
♪Just have fun in the world! I won't turn back♪
♪ فقط استمتع في العالم!  لن أعود ♪
♪What a perfect match♪
♪ يا لها من تطابق مثالي
[Adapted from Jinjiang Wenxuecheng's "Queen Liu Heipang", written by Ge Yang]
[مقتبس من "الملكة ليو هيبانغ" لجينجيانغ وينكسويتشنغ ، بقلم جي يانغ]
[The Legendary Life of Queen Lau]
[الحياة الأسطورية للملكة لاو]
[Episode 30]
[الحلقة 30]
[This work is fictitious. Any resemblance to reality is coincidental]
[هذا العمل وهمي.  أي تشابه مع الواقع هو من قبيل الصدفة]
Why are they here so early?
لماذا هم هنا في وقت مبكر جدا؟
Shuan.
شون.
What's with the big crowd?
ما مع الحشد الكبير؟
I don't know either.
لا اعرف ايضا.
I didn't get to inform everyone yet.
لم أتمكن من إبلاغ الجميع بعد.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
The more, the merrier.
الأكثر والاكثر مرحا.
Are the things ready?
هل الاشياء جاهزة؟
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم يا صاحب الجلالة.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Prince Yunchong is here.
الأمير يونتشونغ هنا.
Your Highness...
صاحب السمو ...
Look.
نظرة.
Young Lady!
إمرأة شابة!
What's happening?
ماذا يحدث؟
I... I don't know.
أنا ... لا أعرف.
This isn't what I prepared.
هذا ليس ما أعددته.
I'm getting intercepted again?
يتم اعتراضني مرة أخرى؟
Yunchong!
يونتشونغ!
He's up in the sky!
إنه في السماء!
Everyone!
الجميع!
I have an announcement to make today.
لدي إعلان اليوم.
We have such a beautiful view
لدينا مثل هذا المنظر الجميل
[Yuanyue Pavilion]
[جناح يوانيوي]
and everyone around
والجميع من حولك
to witness this now.
لتشهد هذا الآن.
His Highness romantic.
سموه رومانسي.
Baiyu!
بايو!
I want you to know
أريدك أن تعلم
that I like you!
أنني مثلك!
Will you marry me?
هل ستتزوجني؟
Young Lady.
إمرأة شابة.
I will treat you well.
سوف أعاملك بشكل جيد.
Baiyu.
بايو.
This is so romantic, Yunchong.
هذا رومانسي جدا ، يونتشونغ.
How romantic.
كم هذا رومنسي.
Miss Baiyu is such a lucky girl.
الآنسة بايو هي فتاة محظوظة.
Baiyu.
بايو.
If there was someone who would do anything for me,
إذا كان هناك شخص ما سيفعل أي شيء من أجلي ،
I could die right now!
يمكن أن أموت الآن!
Baiyu!
بايو!
Will you marry me?
هل ستتزوجني؟
-Marry him!
-تتزوجه!  -تتزوجه!
Young Lady.
إمرأة شابة.
Say yes!
قل نعم!
Marry him, marry him!
الزواج منه ، الزواج منه!
Marry me, marry me!
تزوجني ، تزوجني!
Marry him...
تتزوجه...
Baiyu!
بايو!
What's your answer, Baiyu?
ما هي إجابتك يا بايو؟
[I love you with my whole heart]
[أحبك من كل قلبي]
Baiyu!
بايو!
Hurry!
عجل!
He's up so high.
إنه مرتفع للغاية.
I'm glad I'm not up there.
أنا سعيد لأنني لست هناك.
Are you scared of the height?
هل انت خائف من الارتفاع؟
Yes.
نعم.
I would panic if I were up there.
سأفزع إذا كنت هناك.
Very well...
ممتاز...
Do you really not find the hot air balloon romantic?
هل حقا لا تجد منطاد الهواء الساخن رومانسي؟
It's childish.
إنه طفولي.
I'm glad that I wasn't up there.
أنا سعيد لأنني لم أكن هناك.
Or you might become a widower.
أو قد تصبح أرملًا.
Then, what's romantic for you?
إذن ، ما هو الرومانسية بالنسبة لك؟
Look.
نظرة.
-What is it? -It's so romantic.
-ما هذا؟  -انه رومانسي جدا.
Let's make a heart with our hands.
دعونا نصنع قلبًا بأيدينا.
This is romantic?
هل هذا رومانسي؟
How romantic.
كم هذا رومنسي.
But they all are saying
لكنهم جميعا يقولون
that Yunchong and Baiyu are romantic.
أن Yunchong و Baiyu رومانسيين.
It's their kind of romantic.
إنه نوعهم الرومانسي.
This is our kind of romantic.
هذا هو نوعنا الرومانسي.
♪Your dimples♪
♪ غمازاتك ♪
I get it now.
استلمتها الان.
♪Remind me of something♪
♪ ذكرني بشيء ♪
♪Who can explain the poem to me?♪
♪ من يستطيع أن يشرح لي القصيدة؟
♪Suddenly you light up with a smile♪
♪ فجأة تضيء بابتسامة
♪Another page full of poems♪
♪ صفحة أخرى مليئة بالقصائد ♪
♪What an exuberant vernal scene♪
يا له من مشهد ربيعي غزير ♪
You are right.
أنت محق.
♪If you are sincere and earnest♪
إذا كنت مخلصًا وجادًا ♪
This is our kind of romantic.
هذا هو نوعنا الرومانسي.
♪I'm still greedy♪
♪ ما زلت جشعًا ♪
♪Even in my dreams♪
♪ حتى في أحلامي ♪
You...
أنت...
What brings you here at this hour?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا في هذه الساعة؟
I've done so much today
لقد فعلت الكثير اليوم
and I finally got down from the hot air balloon.
وأخيراً نزلت من منطاد الهواء الساخن.
I'm waiting for your answer.
أنا في انتظار ردكم.
What answer?
ما الجواب؟
I like you.
أنا معجب بك.
Will you marry me?
هل ستتزوجني؟
I...
أنا...
How can you
كيف يمكنك
just say those words so easily?
فقط قل هذه الكلمات بهذه السهولة؟
I've done everything I can.
لقد فعلت كل ما بوسعي.
This is nothing for me.
هذا لا شيء بالنسبة لي.
I...
أنا...
Stop running away.
توقف عن الهرب.
I won't let you get away this time.
لن أدعك تبتعد هذه المرة.
I won't go
لن اذهب
if you don't give me an answer.
إذا لم تعطيني إجابة.
What answer?
ما الجواب؟
Will you marry me or not?
هل تتزوجني أم لا؟
If you say yes,
إذا قلت نعم ،
I will ask Yunchong to issue a decree.
سأطلب من Yunchong إصدار مرسوم.
If you don't say yes...
إذا لم تقل نعم ...
What will you do?
ماذا ستفعل؟
I will ask again tomorrow.
سأطلب مرة أخرى غدا.
I will ask the same question every day
سأطرح نفس السؤال كل يوم
until you say yes.
حتى تقول نعم.
Sure. Go ahead and ask me every day.
بالتأكيد.  تفضل واسألني كل يوم.
You...
أنت...
Are you serious?
هل أنت جاد؟
You're a fool.
أنت أحمق.
This is the book with a signature that you asked for.
هذا هو الكتاب مع التوقيع الذي طلبته.
Here.
هنا.
You haven't answered me yet.
أنت لم تجبني بعد.
Why did she give me this?
لماذا أعطتني هذا؟
[Yes]
[نعم]
Yes?
نعم؟
She said yes!
قالت نعم!
Liu Baiyu said yes!
قال ليو بايو نعم!
Liu Baiyu, you said yes!
ليو بايو ، قلت نعم!
She said yes.
قالت نعم.
She said yes!
قالت نعم!
She agrees to marry me!
هي توافق على الزواج بي!
Liu Baiyu said yes!
قال ليو بايو نعم!
She said yes!
قالت نعم!
He's not such a fool after all.
إنه ليس مثل هذا الأحمق بعد كل شيء.
♪The moon reflected upon the surface of the lake♪
انعكاس القمر على سطح البحيرة
♪Let go of your thoughts♪
♪ تخلَّ عن أفكارك ♪
♪Swallows returning to their nests in the evening♪
طيور السنونو تعود إلى أعشاشها في المساء
♪The soothing cicada sound♪
صوت الزيز المهدئ ♪
♪A crowded corner in the marketplace♪
ركن مزدحم بالسوق ♪
♪People are having fun♪
♪ الناس يستمتعون ♪
♪Lingering emotions♪
♪ عواطف طويلة الأمد ♪
♪And relationships of the world♪
♪ وعلاقات العالم ♪
♪You will soon find out♪
♪ ستكتشف قريبًا
♪I fall for you too early♪
♪ أنا أقع في حبك مبكرًا جدًا ♪
♪And miss your hug♪
♪ وافتقد عناقك ♪
♪That's why I fuss over♪
♪ هذا هو سبب ضجيجي ♪
♪The minute troubles with you♪
♪ لحظة المتاعب معك ♪
Stop drinking, Your Highness.
توقف عن الشرب يا صاحب السمو.
It will look bad for you
سوف تبدو سيئة بالنسبة لك
if someone finds you drinking during the day.
إذا وجدك شخص ما تشرب أثناء النهار.
So what if they do?
إذن ماذا لو فعلوا؟
I would expose everything if they saw me.
سأفضح كل شيء إذا رأوني.
I've had enough.
لقد اكتفيت.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Don't say that.
لا تقل ذلك.
You'll be able to go home
ستكون قادرًا على العودة إلى المنزل
if you found that formula.
إذا وجدت هذه الصيغة.
The rest can go for it if they want.
يمكن للباقي أن يذهبوا إليه إذا أرادوا.
Not me.
ليس انا.
They are all going after it.
كلهم يسعون وراءها.
What are my chances?
ما هي فرصي؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Please stop drinking.
من فضلك توقف عن الشرب.
Being drunk makes you blunder and lose self-control.
كونك في حالة سكر يجعلك تخفق وتفقد ضبط النفس.
Imagine how bad you will look
تخيل كم ستبدو سيئا
if the Empress Dowager sees you.
إذا رآك الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
I don't care.
لا أهتم.
I have nothing to lose.
ليس لدي ما أخسره.
I'm not scared of her.
أنا لا أخاف منها.
Here comes the Empress Dowager.
هنا تأتي الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
Here. Drink it.
هنا.  اشربه.
Come on.
هيا.
This...
هذه...
Hurry!
عجل!
How many times have I told you?
كم مرة قلت لك؟
Being drunk makes you blunder and lose self-control.
كونك في حالة سكر يجعلك تخفق وتفقد ضبط النفس.
Dear Xu.
عزيزي شو.
Why don't you ever listen?
لماذا لا تسمع ابدا؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
It reeks of alcohol here.
تفوح منها رائحة الكحول هنا.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I caught her drinking
أمسكت بها تشرب
during the day.
خلال اليوم.
This is outrageous.
هذا أمر شائن.
She needs to be punished.
هي بحاجة إلى أن تعاقب.
Yes.
نعم.
She deserves it.
أنها تستحق ذلك.
I'll punish her right now.
سأعاقبها الآن.
You... You shall...
أنت ... يجب عليك ...
All right.
حسنا.
That can wait.
يمكن أن ينتظر.
Why don't you go somewhere with me?
لماذا لا تذهب معي الى مكان ما؟
Where?
أين؟
I heard
سمعت
that Liu Xie's wife is staying in the palace for some reason.
أن زوجة ليو شيه تقيم في القصر لسبب ما.
Liu Xie is trying all he can
ليو شيه يحاول كل ما في وسعه
to persuade her to return.
لإقناعها بالعودة.
A lot is going on.
يحدث الكثير.
Really?
هل حقا؟
We have to take a look.
علينا أن نلقي نظرة.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
The hair cleanser from the palace is indeed different.
منظف ​​الشعر من القصر مختلف بالفعل.
It smells great.
رائحته رائعة.
If you like it,
إذا أعجبك ذلك ،
you may bring some back with you.
يمكنك إحضار بعض معك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
The Empress Dowager has arrived.
وصلت الإمبراطورة الأرملة.
Your Majesty, Your Highness.
جلالة الملك ، صاحب السمو.
I didn't know you are here.
لم أكن أعلم أنك هنا.
I heard that the Grand Chancellor is very worried
سمعت أن المستشار الأكبر قلق للغاية
about your stay in the palace.
عن إقامتك في القصر.
That he often sends things over to you
أنه غالبًا ما يرسل لك الأشياء
worrying that you are not used to staying here.
القلق من أنك لست معتادًا على البقاء هنا.
I didn't know
لم أكن أعرف
the inexpressive Grand Chancellor
المستشار الأكبر الخالي من المعنى
is actually a sweet husband.
هو في الواقع زوج لطيف.
He's so thoughtful.
إنه عميق التفكير.
More like he worries too much.
أكثر مثل أنه يقلق كثيرا.
The things in the palace are exquisite.
الأشياء في القصر رائعة.
Just like that hair cleanser.
تمامًا مثل منظف الشعر هذا.
It's much better than what we have.
إنه أفضل بكثير مما لدينا.
You...
أنت...
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
I'm not allowed to use it?
لا يسمح لي باستخدامه؟
No.
رقم.
She even said I can bring some of them home.
قالت حتى إنه يمكنني إحضار بعض منهم إلى المنزل.
Your hairdo...
تسريحة شعرك ...
It looks old-fashioned?
تبدو قديمة الطراز؟
No.
رقم.
It's unique and beautiful.
إنه فريد وجميل.
Really?
هل حقا؟
What do you call this hairdo?
ماذا تسمي هذا التسريحة؟
I thought of it myself.
فكرت في ذلك بنفسي.
Scholar Yang from our village named it.
أطلق عليها العالم يانغ من قريتنا.
It's called Wuman hairdo.
إنه يسمى تسريحة شعر Wuman.
It's very easy.
انه سهل جدا.
You can even do it yourself.
يمكنك حتى أن تفعل ذلك بنفسك.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Really?
هل حقا؟
Will it be trouble
هل ستكون مشكلة
if I wear that hairstyle?
إذا كنت أرتدي تصفيفة الشعر تلك؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
It will look gorgeous.
سوف تبدو رائعة.
I'll do it for you.
سوف افعلها من اجلك.
Very well then.
حسن جدا اذا.
Jinfeng.
جينفنغ.
I get along so well with your mother.
أنا أتعايش بشكل جيد مع والدتك.
Do you mind if she stays in Qianluo Hall
هل تمانع إذا بقيت في قاعة تشيانلوو
for a couple of days?
لبضعة أيام؟
Mother,
الأم،
what do you say?
ماذا تقول؟
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Mother.
الأم.
You can stay longer. No worries.
يمكنك البقاء لفترة أطول.  لا تقلق.
All right.
حسنا.
I heard that she is the new top scorer of the imperial martial examination.
سمعت أنها هداف الامتحان العسكري الامبراطوري الجديد.
from Xiyue Empire,
من إمبراطورية Xiyue ،
the female general, Zhu Tan.
الجنرال تشو تان.
So, she's Zhu Tan
إذن ، إنها تشو تان
who made her name at the borderland.
الذي صنع اسمها على الحدود.
I heard she is Xiyue Empire's first female martial scholar
سمعت أنها أول باحثة عسكرية في إمبراطورية Xiyue
for the last 20 years.
على مدى السنوات العشرين الماضية.
Where's Grand Chancellor Liu?
أين المستشار الكبير ليو؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
Grand Chancellor Liu is to welcome
نرحب بالمستشار الكبير ليو
Xiyue Empire's emissaries into the capital today.
مبعوثو إمبراطورية Xiyue في العاصمة اليوم.
They should be at the palace entrance now.
يجب أن يكونوا عند مدخل القصر الآن.
Why are they not here yet?
لماذا لم يتواجدوا هنا بعد؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
The emissaries are...
المبعوثون ...
Are they here? Where are they?
هل هم هنا؟  أين هم؟
They did arrive,
لقد وصلوا ،
but...
لكن...
But what?
ولكن ماذا؟
But they went to the Grand Chancellor's Residence.
لكنهم ذهبوا إلى مقر إقامة المستشار الأكبر.
What?
ماذا؟
General.
عام.
Official Liu,
ليو الرسمية ،
here are the gifts from the Emperor of Xiyue Empire.
إليكم الهدايا من إمبراطور إمبراطورية Xiyue.
We hope you like it.
نأمل أن تنال إعجابكم.
It's so kind of him.
إنه لطف منه.
This way, please.
من هذا الاتجاه من فضلك.
Here.
هنا.
Xiyue Empire practices equality among men and women.
تمارس Xiyue Empire المساواة بين الرجال والنساء.
Not only men can take part in the imperial martial examination,
لا يمكن للرجال فقط المشاركة في الامتحان العسكري الإمبراطوري ،
women can, too.
يمكن للمرأة أيضًا.
General Zhu is the martial scholar this year.
الجنرال تشو هو الباحث العسكري هذا العام.
The martial scholar.
الباحث العسكري.
It sounds terrific.
يبدو رائعا.
Not only that,
ليس فقط هذا،
I heard that on the second day she became the martial scholar,
سمعت أنها أصبحت عالمة عسكرية في اليوم الثاني ،
she led an army
قادت جيشا
and wiped out the rebels.
وقضت على المتمردين.
She rose to fame with that battle and now everyone knows her name.
صعدت إلى الشهرة مع تلك المعركة والآن يعرف الجميع اسمها.
She came to the capital this time
لقد جاءت إلى العاصمة هذه المرة
because of His Majesty.
بسبب جلالته.
For His Majesty?
لجلالة الملك؟
What for?
لاجل ماذا؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
Don't worry, Your Majesty.
لا تقلق يا جلالة الملك.
It is a tradition of Xiyue Empire for their generals
إنه تقليد إمبراطورية Xiyue لجنرالاتهم
to visit the capital.
لزيارة العاصمة.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
The last female general who visited the capital
آخر جنرال زارت العاصمة
seemed to be 20 years ago.
يبدو أنه قبل 20 عامًا.
And who was that?
ومن كان هذا؟
It's Consort Li.
إنها القرين لي.
She married the Late Emperor not long after.
تزوجت الإمبراطور الراحل بعد فترة وجيزة.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
And you're asking me not to worry?
وأنت تطلب مني ألا أقلق؟
That's not what I meant.
ليس هذا ما قصدته.
You have nothing to worry about.
لديك ما يدعو للقلق.
From what I know,
من ما أعرفه،
that scholar has a round face
هذا العالم له وجه مستدير
and eyes with single eyelids.
وعينان بجفون واحدة.
As for her figure,
أما بالنسبة لشخصيتها ،
she's really built.
لقد بنيت حقًا.
Oh, my goodness.
يا إلهي.
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
Where else?
اين أيضا؟
I have to go or it will be too late!
يجب أن أذهب وإلا سيكون الوقت قد فات!
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Wait for me!
الانتظار لي!
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
I've seen her with my eyes.
لقد رأيتها بعيني.
Zhu Tan is robust.
تشو تان قوي.
She's tanned and stout.
انها سمرة وقوية.
I bet
أراهن
that you've never seen a woman like her.
أنك لم ترَ امرأة مثلها من قبل.
Come to think of it,
تعال نفكر بها،
I think I've seen someone like her somewhere.
أعتقد أنني رأيت شخصًا مثلها في مكان ما.
The point is not how she looks.
النقطة ليست كيف تبدو.
The point is
المقصود هو
she has no respect for you at all.
هي لا تحترمك على الإطلاق.
She brought her entourage
أحضرت حاشيتها
to Liu Xie's residence.
إلى مقر إقامة ليو شيه.
What's more important is that
ما هو أكثر أهمية هو ذلك
Liu Xie didn't refuse either.
لم يرفض Liu Xie أيضًا.
He welcomed her with open arms.
رحب بها بأذرع مفتوحة.
Not only that,
ليس فقط هذا،
Xiyue Empire has paid tribute to us with so much jewelry,
لقد أشادت إمبراطورية Xiyue بالكثير من المجوهرات ،
but it all went into Liu Xie's possession.
لكن كل ذلك ذهب إلى حيازة Liu Xie.
The most important part is,
الجزء الأكثر أهمية هو ،
I heard that Liu Xie
سمعت أن ليو شيه
is arranging a banquet bigger than the national banquet
يرتب مأدبة أكبر من المأدبة الوطنية
to welcome her.
للترحيب بها.
What did Liu Xie say?
ماذا قال ليو شيه؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I did as you told
فعلت كما قلت
and asked him in his residence.
وسأله في محل إقامته.
I asked, "Grand Chancellor,
سألت ، "المستشار الكبير ،
the emissaries from Xiyue Empire came all the way to Donghao Empire.
جاء المبعوثون من إمبراطورية Xiyue على طول الطريق إلى إمبراطورية Donghao.
But they visited your residence first
لكنهم زاروا مكان إقامتك أولاً
instead of the palace.
بدلا من القصر.
Do you think that's appropriate?"
هل تعتقد أن هذا مناسب؟ "
This is what he answered,
هذا ما قاله.
"What's wrong?
"ما هو الخطأ؟
Did I invite them?
هل دعوتهم؟
They were the ones who wanted to visit my residence.
كانوا هم من أرادوا زيارة مسكني.
Do you expect me to chase them out?"
هل تتوقع مني أن أطردهم؟ "
This is infuriating.
هذا أمر مثير للغضب.
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
I think this is good timing.
أعتقد أن هذا توقيت جيد.
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
Meeting an emissary from another nation in private
لقاء مبعوث من دولة أخرى على انفراد
is a capital offense.
هو جريمة كبرى.
Let's get rid of him right there.
دعنا نتخلص منه هناك.
Settle it
حله
once and for all.
مرة واحدة وإلى الأبد.
Do you think it's easy
هل تعتقد أنه سهل
to get rid of Liu Xie?
للتخلص من ليو شيه؟
You made it sound so easy.
لقد جعلتها تبدو سهلة للغاية.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
His Majesty is a cautious man.
جلالة الملك رجل حذر.
Go.
يذهب.
Where are you going, Yunzhang?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب ، Yunzhang؟
To Liu's Residence.
إلى مقر ليو.
We are leaving the palace?
نحن نغادر القصر؟
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
You're leaving the palace?
أنت تغادر القصر؟
How do you know?
كيف علمت بذلك؟
To my father's place?
إلى مكان والدي؟
How did you know that too?
كيف عرفت ذلك أيضًا؟
To meet General Zhu?
للقاء الجنرال تشو؟
How do you know everything?
كيف تعرف كل شيء؟
How dare you?
كيف تجرؤ؟
What about it?
ماذا عنها؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
They can't do anything to me.
لا يمكنهم فعل أي شيء بي.
I will do something to you.
سأفعل شيئًا لك.
Our two guests have traveled so far
سافر ضيفينا حتى الآن
and brought me so many gifts.
وجلبت لي الكثير من الهدايا.
I have nothing to repay
ليس لدي ما أسدده
but some liquor to express my gratitude.
لكن بعض الخمور للتعبير عن امتناني.
Here.
هنا.
Official Liu,
ليو الرسمية ،
we do things differently than you people.
نحن نفعل الأشياء بشكل مختلف عنكم.
We don't beat around the bush.
نحن لا نتغلب على الأدغال.
Yes, you are a straightforward person.
نعم ، أنت شخص صريح.
What are your requests?
ما هي طلباتك؟
Our Lord has given a decree.
لقد أصدر ربنا مرسوما.
Marriage alliance, cession,
تحالف الزواج ، تنازل ،
and the name list.
وقائمة الأسماء.
If you can fulfill all of these,
إذا كان بإمكانك تحقيق كل ذلك ،
he will assist you
سوف يساعدك
in achieving what you want.
في تحقيق ما تريد.
Well...
نحن سوف...
You are a wise man.
أنت رجل حكيم.
Our Lord has also said
قال ربنا ايضا
that you both have worked together for many years.
أنتما عملا معًا لسنوات عديدة.
You know each other very well.
أنت تعرف بعضكما البعض جيدًا.
With your power,
بقوتك ،
you should be able to fulfill our requests.
يجب أن تكون قادرًا على تلبية طلباتنا.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
But...
ولكن...
What is holding you back?
ما الذى يؤخرك؟
What if I don't want to?
ماذا لو كنت لا تريد أن؟
He knew you would say that.
كان يعلم أنك ستقول ذلك.
Therefore...
وبالتالي...
General.
عام.
That was merely a joke.
كانت مجرد مزحة.
Please don't take it seriously.
من فضلك لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد.
He got it wrong.
لقد أخطأ.
Why would I say no?
لماذا أقول لا؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I intend to do so and I have the capability.
أنوي القيام بذلك ولدي القدرة.
Why don't you also tell me
لماذا لا تخبرني أيضًا
what you intend to do, Grand Chancellor?
ماذا تنوي أن تفعل أيها المستشار الكبير؟
You're here, Your Majesty.
أنت هنا يا جلالة الملك.
Allow me to introduce.
اسمحوا لي أن أقدم.
This is the Emperor of Donghao Empire.
هذا هو إمبراطور إمبراطورية Donghao.
Please give your regards.
من فضلك قدم تحياتك.
The emissaries attended the banquet here
حضر المبعوثون المأدبة هنا
instead of entering the palace.
بدلا من دخول القصر.
Perhaps the food served here
ربما يتم تقديم الطعام هنا
is better than the Imperial Palace's.
أفضل من القصر الإمبراطوري.
The chef in Liu Residence is my disciple.
الطاهي في سكن Liu هو تلميذي.
You have misunderstood, Your Majesty.
لقد أسأت فهمك يا جلالة الملك.
We don't mean that.
نحن لا نعني ذلك.
It was late when we arrived in the capital.
كان الوقت متأخرًا عندما وصلنا إلى العاصمة.
We were afraid of interrupting,
كنا خائفين من المقاطعة ،
so we decided to enter the palace tomorrow.
لذلك قررنا دخول القصر غدا.
I hope you understand our concern.
أتمنى أن تتفهم قلقنا.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
General Zhu, I heard that you
الجنرال تشو ، سمعت ذلك
brought abundant gifts on this trip,
جلبت هدايا وفيرة في هذه الرحلة ،
and you also brought with you 3,000 warriors from Xiyue Empire.
وقد أحضرت معك أيضًا 3000 محارب من إمبراطورية Xiyue.
Are you thinking that the guards in our palace
هل تعتقد أن الحراس في قصرنا
are weak,
ضعيفة،
so you would like to fight them?
لذلك كنت ترغب في محاربتهم؟
That's delusional!
هذا وهمي!
Bring it on.
اجلبه.
The warriors were to transport
كان على المحاربين أن ينقلوا
the gifts, Your Majesty.
الهدايا يا جلالة الملك.
You worry too much.
انت تقلق كثيرا.
All right.
حسنا.
I believe we have cleared the misunderstanding.
أعتقد أننا أزلنا سوء الفهم.
Everyone should be happy now.
يجب أن يكون الجميع سعداء الآن.
General Zhu is not only physically strong,
الجنرال تشو ليس فقط قويًا جسديًا ،
but she is also good at talking.
لكنها أيضًا جيدة في الكلام.
She got away from such trouble
لقد أفلتت من مثل هذه المشاكل
with just a few words.
ببضع كلمات.
What do you
ماذا انت
take Donghao Empire and me for?
خذ إمبراطورية Donghao وأنا؟
Jing.
جينغ.
That female general
أن جنرال
looks like a familiar face.
يبدو وكأنه وجه مألوف.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Are you asking me?
هل تسالني؟
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I am Zhu Tan.
أنا تشو تان.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
You are Zhu Tan?
أنت تشو تان؟
That's right, Your Majesty.
هذا صحيح يا صاحب الجلالة.
I am indeed Zhu Tan.
أنا بالفعل تشو تان.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
I am the General of Vanguard, Li Liang.
أنا جنرال الطليعة ، لي ليانغ.
If Your Majesty is unhappy about what happened today,
إذا كان جلالتك غير سعيد بما حدث اليوم ،
it's our fault
هذا خطأنا
for not knowing better.
لعدم معرفة أفضل.
It's late now.
فوات الآن.
Please return and get some rest, Your Majesty.
يرجى العودة والحصول على قسط من الراحة ، جلالة الملك.
Tomorrow morning,
غدا صباحا،
we will meet you in the palace
سنلتقي بك في القصر
and apologize for our wrongdoing.
ونعتذر عن مخالفاتنا.
I beg for your forgiveness.
استميحك عذرا.
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
I think she has a point.
أعتقد أن لديها وجهة نظر.
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
I think General Zhu is right.
أعتقد أن الجنرال تشو على حق.
That's all for today's banquet.
هذا كل شيء لمأدبة اليوم.
We shall take our leave.
سنأخذ إجازتنا.
Wait.
انتظر.
Wait for what?
انتظر ماذا؟
It's late.
الوقت متاخر.
You may go.
يمكنك الذهاب.
What's the meaning of this, Grand Chancellor?
ما معنى هذا أيها المستشارة الكبرى؟
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
I don't want you to embarrass yourself here.
لا أريدك أن تحرج نفسك هنا.
The Emperor is trying to punish an emissary
الإمبراطور يحاول معاقبة مبعوث
at the Grand Chancellor's Residence?
في مقر إقامة المستشار الكبير؟
Have you thought about
هل فكرت في
who will be benefited
من سيستفيد
and who will be embarrassed by this?
ومن سيحرج من هذا؟
You are worried about my authority?
أنت قلق بشأن سلطتي؟
If I am not,
إذا لم أكن كذلك ،
I would have sent someone to chase you out.
كنت سأرسل شخصًا ليطاردك.
How insolent.
يا له من وقاحة.
Right back at you.
عدت إليك.
Don't forget.
لا تنسى.
Who do the courtiers listen to?
إلى من يستمع رجال البلاط؟
Who does the army listen to?
لمن يستمع الجيش؟
Liu Xie.
ليو شيه.
I thought
اعتقدت
my father has his reason for leaving me with you.
والدي لديه سبب لتركني معك.
But I understand now.
لكني أفهم الآن.
Your ambition is obvious.
طموحك واضح.
You taught me to be a good man and a good ruler.
لقد علمتني أن أكون رجلًا صالحًا وحاكمًا صالحًا.
But you don't actually mean it.
لكنك لا تعني ذلك في الواقع.
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
You are right
أنت محق
but also wrong.
ولكن أيضا خطأ.
If I do intend to rebel,
إذا كنت أنوي التمرد ،
what can you do about it?
ماذا يمكنك أن تفعل بهذا الشأن؟
But I meant what I taught you.
لكنني قصدت ما علمتك إياه.
That's because I don't like to suppress the weak
هذا لأنني لا أحب قمع الضعيف
as the stronger one.
كأقوى.
I want to beat
أريد أن أتفوق
the Emperor who has matured into a fully capable ruler,
الإمبراطور الذي نضج ليصبح حاكمًا كامل الأهلية ،
instead of a child emperor
بدلا من إمبراطور طفل
who knows nothing.
من لا يعرف شيئا.
It's late and he's not back yet.
لقد تأخر الوقت ولم يعد بعد.
This is nerve-wracking.
هذا محطم للأعصاب.
Is he really going to ignore me?
هل سيتجاهلني حقًا؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It's late.
الوقت متاخر.
We can wait until tomorrow.
يمكننا الانتظار حتى الغد.
No.
رقم.
What if
ماذا إذا
he got seduced by Zhu?
حصل على إغرائه من قبل Zhu؟
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
I have to show him who the real general is.
يجب أن أوضح له من هو الجنرال الحقيقي.
What is that sound?
ما هذا الصوت؟
Whatever.
ايا كان.
I have more important things to do tonight.
لدي أشياء أكثر أهمية لأفعلها الليلة.
Why are you sitting there with a dagger?
لماذا تجلس هناك مع خنجر؟
-You...
-أنت ... -أنت ...
You first.
أنت أولاً.
You say it first.
قلها أولا.
Why were you sitting there
لماذا كنت جالسا هناك
holding a dagger?
ممسكا بخنجر؟
It's because of you.
هذا بسببك.
You think someone is trying to kill you?
هل تعتقد أن هناك من يحاول قتلك؟
Do you really think Liu Xie might send someone to kill you?
هل تعتقد حقًا أن Liu Xie قد يرسل شخصًا لقتلك؟
I have to be cautious.
يجب أن أكون حذرا.
I don't think he will.
لا أعتقد أنه سيفعل.
Why?
لماذا ا؟
Since I was little, my mother has been saying
منذ أن كنت صغيرة ، كانت والدتي تقول
that my father is a good man.
أن والدي رجل طيب.
Let me ask you.
دعني أسألك.
One day,
يوم واحد،
if I decide to stand up against your father,
إذا قررت الوقوف ضد والدك ،
who will you side with?
مع من سوف تنحاز؟
I'll see how it goes.
سأرى كيف ستسير الامور.
I will side with the one who is good to me.
سأقف مع من هو جيد بالنسبة لي.
I'm being serious.
انا جاد.
I'm here to ask you something serious, too.
أنا هنا لأطلب منك شيئًا جادًا أيضًا.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
You had a long meeting with General Zhu.
كان لديك اجتماع طويل مع الجنرال تشو.
What did you two talk about?
عن ماذا تحدثتما الاثنان؟
Nothing.
لا شئ.
Nothing?
لا شئ؟
You both talked for so long.
كلاكما تحدثا لفترة طويلة.
There must be something.
يجب أن يكون هناك شيء.
There was really nothing.
لم يكن هناك شيء حقًا.
No way. You have to tell me.
مستحيل.  عليك أن تخبرني.
I said there was nothing.
قلت لم يكن هناك شيء.
You're being suspicious.
أنت متشكك.
Whatever you think.
مهما كان رأيك.
I'm going to bed.
انا ذاهب الى السرير.
I have to attend the assembly tomorrow.
لا بد لي من حضور الجمعية غدا.
No.
رقم.
You have to tell me.
عليك أن تخبرني.
Spit it out.
ألفظه، أبصقها أبصق عليها.
About what?
عن ما؟
Get up.
استيقظ.
I will hit you with the pillow if you don't.
سأضربك بالوسادة إذا لم تفعل.
-Tell me! -I...
-أخبرني!  -أنا...
Are you telling me or not?
هل تخبرني ام لا؟
Say it!
قلها!
My lord.
ربي.
You'll have to call me "Your Highness"
عليك أن تناديني ب "صاحب السمو"
after these two hours.
بعد هاتين الساعتين.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم سموكم.
If you listen to me,
إذا استمعت إلي ،
I will grant you
سأمنحك
anything you want.
اي شيء تريده.
We hope you accept our tribute.
نأمل أن تقبل تكريمنا.
[Hanyuan Hall]
[Hanyuan Hall] نتمنى أن تقبل تكريمنا.
You may rise, General.
يمكنك النهوض أيها الجنرال.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
On the orders of our Lord,
بأمر ربنا ،
we have brought a hundred fine horses,
لقد أحضرنا مائة خيل رائع ،
a thousand cows and goats,
ألف بقرة وماعز ،
and ten thousand gold.
وعشرة آلاف ذهب.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
our Lord has also said
قال ربنا ايضا
that the gifts this time
أن الهدايا هذه المرة
are not just a form of paying tribute,
ليست مجرد شكل من أشكال التكريم ،
but it is also a dowry.
ولكنه أيضًا مهر.
Dowry?
مهر؟
Donghao and Xiyue have had good relations for generations.
تتمتع Donghao و Xiyue بعلاقات جيدة منذ أجيال.
Marriage alliances were arranged many times.
تم ترتيب تحالفات الزواج عدة مرات.
Twenty years ago, General Li married into the palace.
قبل عشرين عاما ، تزوج الجنرال لي في القصر.
She married the Late Emperor
تزوجت من الإمبراطور الراحل
and gave birth to a successor.
وأنجبت خليفتها.
But for the last 20 years,
ولكن على مدار العشرين عامًا الماضية ،
this tradition seems to have been to a halt.
يبدو أن هذا التقليد قد توقف.
We find it regretful.
نجدها مؤسفة.
Thus, for our diplomatic relations,
وهكذا ، بالنسبة لعلاقاتنا الدبلوماسية ،
I hope you accept the dowry.
أرجو قبول المهر.
And this dowry belongs to?
وهذا المهر يعود ل؟
It's for me.
أنه لي.
A marriage alliance?
تحالف زواج؟
I propose to marry Your Majesty as your consort
أقترح الزواج من جلالتك كرفيق لك
to maintain our diplomatic relations.
للحفاظ على علاقاتنا الدبلوماسية.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Your Majesty!
جلالة الملك!
Your Majesty...
جلالة الملك ...
Bad news, Your Majesty!
أخبار سيئة يا جلالة الملك!
What is it?
ما هذا؟
She's here, Your Majesty.
إنها هنا يا جلالة الملك.
Who is?
الذي هو؟
The... The general is here.
... الجنرال هنا.
The general?
الجنرال؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك ،
it was our tradition to have a marriage alliance.
كان تقليدنا أن يكون لدينا تحالف زواج.
But the Late Emperor had established a rule.
لكن الإمبراطور الراحل وضع قاعدة.
That Consort Li
تلك القرين لي
will be the last consort from Xiyue Empire.
سيكون القرين الأخير من إمبراطورية Xiyue.
You must not take another wife.
يجب ألا تأخذ زوجة أخرى.
Yes.
نعم.
I still remember the rule by the Late Emperor.
ما زلت أتذكر حكم الإمبراطور الراحل.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Yes.
نعم.
We have a report from outside the city.
لدينا تقرير من خارج المدينة.
The 5,000 warriors from Xiyue Empire
5000 محارب من إمبراطورية Xiyue
refused to return after transporting the gifts.
رفض العودة بعد نقل الهدايا.
They even built a base camp
حتى أنهم بنوا معسكرًا أساسيًا
and practiced martial art every day. They can be heard even from far away.
ويمارس فنون الدفاع عن النفس كل يوم.  يمكن سماعها حتى من بعيد.
They are clearly provoking us.
من الواضح أنهم يستفزوننا.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I think
أظن
we can't just follow the past rules blindly.
لا يمكننا فقط اتباع القواعد الماضية بشكل أعمى.
Xiyue Empire's army is getting stronger.
جيش إمبراطورية Xiyue يزداد قوة.
It's bad timing
إنه توقيت سيء
to go on a war with them now.
للذهاب في حرب معهم الآن.
A mere army with 5,000 warriors
مجرد جيش بخمسة آلاف محارب
is enough to frighten you this much.
يكفي لتخويفك بهذا القدر.
I suggest you quit the Minister of War.
أقترح أن تستقيل وزير الحرب.
Yunzhang.
Yunzhang.
We have an urgent report from the frontline.
لدينا تقرير عاجل من الخطوط الأمامية.
It just arrived.
لقد وصل للتو.
Read it.
اقرأها.
Xiyue's army of 300,000 warriors is marching toward the border of West Mountain.
جيش Xiyue المكون من 300000 محارب يسير نحو حدود West Mountain.
They have been marching for more than 10 days.
لقد كانوا يسيرون منذ أكثر من 10 أيام.
We only have 30,000 soldiers on our side.
لدينا 30 ألف جندي فقط إلى جانبنا.
We are outnumbered.
نحن فاق عددنا.
We need your order, Your Majesty.
نحن بحاجة إلى طلبك ، جلالة الملك.
When will the backup arrive?
متى ستصل النسخة الاحتياطية؟
Do we go to war or not?
هل نذهب للحرب أم لا؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Do you have something to say?
هل لديك ما تقوله؟
I think...
أظن...
Your Majesty...
جلالة الملك ...
Bad news!
اخبار سيئة!
Say it.
قلها.
It has begun.
وقد بدأ ذلك.
What?
ماذا؟
It has started!
وقد بدأ!
Who exactly are you?
من انت بالضبط
Why do you care?
لماذا تهتم؟
I'm here for General Zhu.
أنا هنا من أجل الجنرال تشو.
I thought Donghao Empire was a nation of etiquette.
اعتقدت أن إمبراطورية Donghao كانت أمة ذات آداب.
I didn't know
لم أكن أعرف
there was a savage in the palace.
كان هناك وحشية في القصر.
Savage?
متوحش؟
You stole my husband and you expect me to be nice?
لقد سرقت زوجي وتتوقع مني أن أكون لطيفًا؟
I...
أنا...
What?
ماذا؟
Ask Zhu Tan to come out.
اطلب من Zhu Tan أن يخرج.
Or I'll make you a cripple.
أو سأجعلك مشلولا.
Go for it, Your Majesty!
اذهب من أجلها ، جلالة الملك!
Be careful, Your Majesty.
كن حذرا ، جلالة الملك.
Go for it!
أذهب خلفها !
You can do it, Your Majesty.
يمكنك فعل ذلك يا جلالة الملك.
General Zhu.
الجنرال تشو.
How long more do you plan to fight her?
كم من الوقت تخطط لمحاربتها؟
You're General Zhu?
أنت الجنرال تشو؟
Your Majesty?
جلالة الملك؟
I can't hold it any longer.
لا أستطيع تحمله أكثر من ذلك.
Jinfeng!
جينفنغ!
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
I'm okay.
أنا بخير.
Are you hurt?
هل تأذيت؟
General Zhu,
الجنرال تشو ،
the Queen is quick-tempered.
الملكة سريعة الغضب.
Please forgive her.
أرجوك سامحها.
I wouldn't have fought you if I had known earlier.
لم أكن لأقاتلك لو كنت قد عرفت سابقًا.
Sufang gave me the wrong information.
أعطاني سوفانج المعلومات الخاطئة.
You look so different.
أنت تبدو مختلفة جدا.
What did you imagine I look like?
ماذا تخيلت أن أبدو؟
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
This is fine. This is okay.
هذا جيد.  هذا جيد.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
It's a pleasure meeting the Queen.
إنه لمن دواعي سروري مقابلة الملكة.
Don't you worry.
لا تقلق.
We will get along in the palace.
سوف نتعايش في القصر.
I won't put you on the spot.
لن أضعك على الفور.
Sure, no problem.
بالتأكيد لا مشكلة.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Your Majesty has accepted the dowry,
لقد قبلت جلالة الملك المهر ،
I shall take my leave
سوف آخذ إجازتي
and wait for the decree of the marriage.
وانتظر مرسوم الزواج.
Tighten your fist and swing it swiftly.
شد قبضتك وأرجحها بسرعة.
Like this.
مثله.
Go.
يذهب.
Firm up your posture.
ثبّت وضعيتك.
Your foundation is terrible.
مؤسستك سيئة للغاية.
I'm not like you.
أنا لست مثلك.
You have a mentor and the time to practice.
لديك مرشد ووقت للممارسة.
I have to learn this in secret.
يجب أن أتعلم هذا في الخفاء.
Or my father would scold me if he knew.
أو كان والدي يوبخني إذا علم.
Master Zhu will be surprised
سوف يفاجأ السيد تشو
if his family of literary scholars
إذا كان أهله من علماء الأدب
has a daughter like you.
لديه ابنة مثلك.
You hate studying and only want to learn martial arts.
أنت تكره الدراسة وتريد فقط تعلم فنون الدفاع عن النفس.
There's no fun studying.
ليس هناك متعة في الدراسة.
I want to be a martial scholar when I grow up.
أريد أن أصبح عالمًا عسكريًا عندما أكبر.
You did well.
لقد أبليت حسنا.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكرا لك جلالة الملك.
It's about time.
إنه بشأن الوقت.
I would like to see
أود رؤية
what that young Emperor can do.
ما يمكن أن يفعله ذلك الإمبراطور الشاب.
Everything is ready outside the city.
كل شيء جاهز خارج المدينة.
We will return to the camp.
سنعود إلى المخيم.
What about...
ماذا عن...
Don't cross the line.
لا تتخطى الخط.
Yes.
نعم.
I'm just worried that if we don't return to the inn,
أنا قلقة فقط من أننا إذا لم نعد إلى النزل ،
the young Emperor will get suspicious.
سوف يشك الإمبراطور الشاب.
Let him be.
دعه يكون.
I can't wait for him to lead an army now.
لا استطيع الانتظار حتى يقود جيشا الآن.
I would like to see
أود رؤية
if that old fox, Liu Xie
إذا كان ذلك الثعلب العجوز ، ليو شيه
would overthrow the Emperor or not.
من شأنه أن يطيح بالإمبراطور أم لا.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
His Majesty is outside the hall.
جلالة الملك خارج القاعة.
Would you like to see him?
هل تود رؤيته؟
No.
رقم.
The dessert is outside the hall, too.
الحلوى خارج القاعة أيضًا.
Would you like to have some?
هل ترغب في الحصول على بعض؟
No.
رقم.
Stop talking and stop being annoying.
توقف عن الكلام وتوقف عن الانزعاج.
Your Majesty, why don't just leave for now?
جلالة الملك ، لماذا لا تغادر الآن؟
You can explain to her
يمكنك أن تشرح لها
after she calmed down a bit.
بعد أن هدأت قليلا.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
[Xiangluo Hall]
[قاعة Xiangluo]
You're still here, Grand Chancellor.
ما زلت هنا ، أيها المستشار الكبير.
My daughter is unhappy.
ابنتي غير سعيدة.
Of course
بالطبع
I'd have to come and have a look.
يجب أن آتي وألقي نظرة.
Do you have any good plans in mind?
هل لديك أي خطط جيدة في الاعتبار؟
You said
أنت قلت
that you want to beat me when I've become fully capable.
أنك تريد أن تهزمني عندما أصبح قادرًا تمامًا.
Let me tell you today.
دعني أخبرك اليوم.
You will regret this decision one day.
سوف تندم على هذا القرار ذات يوم.
Because I will win.
لأنني سأفوز.
Let's focus on our tasks today.
دعونا نركز على مهامنا اليوم.
We haven't sorted out the main issue.
لم نقم بتسوية المشكلة الرئيسية.
So let's not talk about other matters.
لذلك دعونا لا نتحدث عن أمور أخرى.
You want to persuade Jinfeng
تريد إقناع Jinfeng
to agree to the marriage, right?
بالموافقة على الزواج ، أليس كذلك؟
It's impossible, Grand Chancellor.
إنه مستحيل أيها المستشار الكبير.
Even if Jinfeng agrees,
حتى لو وافقت Jinfeng ،
I will not.
لن أفعل.
General Zhu is a rare beauty.
جنرال تشو هو جمال نادر.
It's a good thing
انه شيء جيد
if she gets into the harem as your consort.
إذا دخلت الحريم كزوجك.
Xiyue Empire has been sending so many women
كانت إمبراطورية Xiyue ترسل الكثير من النساء
into the capital for so many years.
في العاصمة لسنوات عديدة.
They either work in the palace
إما أنهم يعملون في القصر
or marry the officials.
أو الزواج من المسؤولين.
Do you think I don't know
هل تعتقد أنني لا أعرف
what's on their mind?
ما الذي يدور في أذهانهم؟
And now,
و الأن،
you want someone to watch me by my side.
تريد أن يراقبني أحد بجانبي.
Do you think I'll allow that?
هل تعتقد أنني سأسمح بذلك؟
You're not such a fool after all.
أنت لست أحمق بعد كل شيء.
Grand Chancellor.
المستشار الأكبر.
If you want to fight me,
إذا كنت تريد أن تقاتلني ،
please understand that
من فضلك تفهم هذا
I'm no longer the naive child
لم أعد الطفل الساذج
from ten years ago.
منذ عشر سنوات.
You are absolutely right.
انت على حق تماما.
First, understand your enemy before fighting them.
أولاً ، افهم عدوك قبل قتاله.
You
أنت
should try to understand me first.
يجب أن تحاول فهمي أولاً.
Jinfeng wouldn't agree.
لن توافق Jinfeng.
Who said we will need Jinfeng's permission?
من قال أننا سنحتاج إذن جينفينج؟
You are my son-in-law and you want another wife?
أنت زوج ابنتي وتريد زوجة أخرى؟
In your dreams.
في احلامك.
♪Only second to the Emperor♪
♪ في المرتبة الثانية بعد الإمبراطور ♪
♪Anyone who's against it should back off♪
♪ أي شخص ضدها يجب أن يتراجع
♪I'll make a face and fear no heaven and earth♪
♪ سأصنع وجهًا ولا أخاف السماء والأرض
♪I'll let you go for now♪
♪ سأتركك تذهب الآن ♪
♪I'm not a motherly model♪
♪ أنا لست عارضة أزياء
♪Nor am I the most beautiful lady♪
♪ ولست أجمل سيدة
♪Who says those of humble origin can't be elegant?♪
♪ من يقول أن من هم من أصول متواضعة لا يمكن أن يكونوا أنيقين؟
♪Bring it on. Let's make a big bet♪
اجلبه.  لنقم برهان كبير ♪
♪To be a huge winner♪
♪ أن تكون فائزًا كبيرًا
♪A couple of quarrelsome lovers♪
♪ زوجان من العشاق المشاكسين ♪
♪An odd coincidence became a much-told tale♪
أصبحت مصادفة غريبة حكاية يكثر الحديث عنها
♪Holding bad cards yet I play well still♪
♪ أحمل بطاقات سيئة ولكني ألعب بشكل جيد ♪
♪Accept the plot twist♪
♪ اقبل تطور الحبكة ♪
♪Cut all the romantic themes♪
♪ قص كل المواضيع الرومانسية ♪
♪To talk about love is childish♪
الحديث عن الحب طفولي ♪
♪I shall redefine peerless elegance♪
♪ سأعيد تعريف الأناقة منقطعة النظير
♪Are you ready?♪
♪ هل أنت جاهز؟
♪Tremble, my rivals♪
ارتجف يا منافسي
♪Look, the phoenix in the sky is actually a little crow♪
♪ انظر ، طائر الفينيق في السماء هو في الواقع غراب صغير
♪Surprising the world with its talent♪
يفاجئ العالم بموهبته
♪Experiencing the ups and downs♪
♪ تجربة الصعود والهبوط ♪
♪In return for a wiser life♪
مقابل حياة أكثر حكمة ♪
♪Don't ever look down on the little crow♪
♪ لا تنظر أبدًا إلى الغراب الصغير
♪She wears the crown and controls the world♪
ترتدي التاج وتتحكم في العالم
♪Striking back♪
♪ الرد ♪
♪To be the head of the harem♪
أن يكون رأس الحريم ♪
♪Look, the phoenix in the sky is actually a little crow♪
♪ انظر ، طائر الفينيق في السماء هو في الواقع غراب صغير
♪Surprising the world with its talent♪
يفاجئ العالم بموهبته
♪Experiencing the ups and downs♪
♪ تجربة الصعود والهبوط ♪
♪In return for a wiser life♪
مقابل حياة أكثر حكمة ♪
♪Don't ever look down on the little crow♪
♪ لا تنظر أبدًا إلى الغراب الصغير
♪She wears the crown and controls the world♪
ترتدي التاج وتتحكم في العالم
♪Striking back♪
♪ الرد ♪
♪To be the head of the harem♪
أن يكون رأس الحريم ♪
♪Little crow♪
♪ غراب صغير ♪
♪Dear little crow♪
♪ عزيزي الغراب الصغير ♪
♪Striking back to be the head of the harem♪
الضرب على رأس الحريم
♪Little crow♪
♪ غراب صغير ♪
[Adapted from Jinjiang Wenxuecheng's "Queen Liu Heipang", written by Ge Yang]
[مقتبس من "الملكة ليو هيبانغ" لجينجيانغ وينكسويتشنغ ، بقلم جي يانغ]